what's going on everybody welcome back
to another one and in this video we're
going to be doing a little bit of a
product review on the Pflueger supreme
XT and in this video I'm going to be
giving you my general thoughts on this
reel and if you stay to the very end of
the video we're going to be deciding
whether or not we think that this reel
is worth buying or not worth buying so
stay tuned we're going to get to some of
the action here and we're going to talk
about everything that this reel has to
offer okay so starting off just talking
about some of the main components of
this reel this reel is offered in a 25
30 35 and 40 series so whether you're
looking just for an all-around reel or
if you're looking to catch big fish or
small fish it has you covered because
you can go from a small sized reel up to
you know a really big one if you're
looking to do some deep sea fishing or
something like that so it's definitely
got you covered there which is something
very notable to mention but as we talk
about the next thing the gear ratio on
this reel if you're looking at the 30 35
or 40 sized reels those are going to
come in at a 6 2 1 and this is a 30 so
this reel would be a six two one which
is pretty standard for the spinning reel
Market however if you go to the 25 it's
going to be a five two one which is
honestly I think it's okay too because
you're going to get a little bit a
little bit slower reel but it is fast
enough so you know if you want to run
with crankbaits or if you want to do
anything like that the 621 has you
covered I don't think you have to worry
about it being too fast because if
you're looking to Slow Roll you know
some spinner baits or anything like that
it definitely is able to do so now some
of the components of this reel this is
one of the things that probably makes
this real really shine in my opinion is
that the internals are made of really
high quality material so the inside of
this reel including the body rotor and
side plates are made of magnesium and
that makes this real super super
lightweight and not only that but if you
take a look at the handle the handle is
made of carbon fiber now that carbon
fiber makes this real super super
lightweight and it also offers an
aluminum spool and on the inside of the
spool there's some rubber ridges so if
you're running braided line you don't
have to worry about putting tape on your
line or you know doing some special knot
or anything like that you don't have to
put a backing of monofilament because
those rubber backstops are going to make
it so that your braid doesn't slip on
the spool which is honestly super cool
I've never had a reel that's did that
before or had that before and I thought
it was super nice because I do run braid
on most of my setups but with the
internals of this reel being made of
magnesium it makes it extremely durable
for fresh water and salt water use so if
you're looking for reel that's going to
last you a long time this is definitely
a very quality Contender so I'd like to
get into the casting of this reel it
seems to be super smooth I love the
casting you can cast a really long
distances with it I have like a 20 or 30
pound braid on here and it does great I
mean I can cast super super far and the
retrieve are awesome because there's 10
ball bearings in here it feels amazing
it's super smooth when you reel it in
and the Bale opens and closes super
super easily you don't have to force it
open and you don't have to force it
closed it's almost like it happens on
its own and I think that's one of the
reasons I like this reel so much is just
because of the quality components that
are in it it makes for a rod that's
going to last a long long time and I
think you're really paying for the
longevity of this reel because it's made
of quality stuff and you get what you
pay for now this reel comes in right
around like 150 to 170 dollars depending
on if it's on sale and that kind of
thing which honestly is the only
downside to this reel it's a bit pricey
but like I said you get what you pay for
if you're looking for a reel that is
Gonna Last you a long time for years to
come and not worry about it not working
and that kind of thing and if you're
really just looking for Quality this is
definitely going to be worth it for you
I would 100 percent recommend checking
out the fluger supreme
XT it is a top of its class reel and I
can't say good enough things about it so
if you guys enjoyed this video make sure
you subscribe to the channel and like
the video and we'll see you guys in the
next one peace